A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Office of the Secretary of Commerce and Trade, 1994-2006 (bulk 2002-2005)
Library of Virginia
- VIII. Governor's Opportunity Fund Files, 2001-2006., Extent: 2.75 cu. ft. (6 boxes) (Box 103-108)
  - Governor's Opportunity Fund
    - General Dynamics Armament and Technical Products Division, Smyth County, 2003-2004 (Box 103, Folder 71)
    - Generie Systems, Pulaski County, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 72)
    - Gerdau Ameristeel, King George County, 2004-2005 (Box 103, Folder 73)
    - Global Lumber and Manufacturing, Lunenburg County, 2004 (Box 103, Folder 74)
    - Globaltex Inc., Henry County, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 75)
    - Guardian Industries Inc., Galax, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 76)
    - Grand Vehicle Works, Warren County, 2002 (Box 103, Folder 77)
    - Leak-Goforth Company, LLC, Washington County, 2002 (Box 103, Folder 78)
    - HBO Pictures, Iron-Jawed Angels, 2002 (Box 103, Folder 79)
    - Harden Manufacturing Corporation, Mecklenburg County, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 80)
    - Harmen/Becker Automotive, Albemarle County, 2004 (Box 103, Folder 81)
    - Harvest Pharmaceuticals, Grayson County, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 82)
    - Project Heart (Care Rehab), Charlotte County, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 83)
    - Holset Engineering Co. Ltd., Suffolk and Portsmouth, 2005 (Box 103, Folder 84)
    - Home Depot, Frederick County, 2002-2003 (Box 103, Folder 85)
    - Hooker Furniture, Martinsville, 2005 (Box 103, Folder 86)
    - Home Shopping Network, Franklin County, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 87)
    - Howard Miller Company, Henry County, 2005 (Box 103, Folder 88)
    - Hudd Distribution Services, Inc., 2002-2003 (Box 103, Folder 89)
    - IBM Corporation, Fairfax County, 2004 (Box 103, Folder 90)
    - ICM Controls, Pulaski County, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 97)
    - Illinois Tool Works, Botetourt County, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 98)
    - Inbound Call Center, Norfolk, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 99)
    - Infineon Technologies, Henrico County, 2004 (Box 103, Folder 100)
    - Invoe' Graphics, Inc., Bristol, 2002 (Box 103, Folder 101)
    - Insulair, Inc., Dinwiddie County, 2005 (Box 103, Folder 102)
    - Integrity Windows, Inc., Roanoke County, 2002-2003 (Box 103, Folder 103)
    - International BioFuels, Inc., Greensville, 2005 (Box 103, Folder 104)
    - Intermet Corporation, Radford, 2006 (Box 103, Folder 105)
    - ITT Industries Night Vision, Roanoke County, 2005 (Box 103, Folder 106)
    - James Hardie Building Products, Pulaski County, 2004-2005 (Box 103, Folder 107)
    - Johnstown America Corporation, City of Roanoke, 2004-2005 (Box 103, Folder 108)
    - Project KLG2, Richmond MSA, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 109)
    - KVP Falcon, Prince George County, 2002 (Box 103, Folder 110)
    - Kentucky Derby Hosiery, Carroll County, 2002 (Box 103, Folder 111)
    - Keystone Dyeing and Finishing, Inc., Orange County, 2002 (Box 103, Folder 112)
    - King Pharmaceuticals, Washington County, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 113)
    - Project Kitchen (Illinois Tool Works), Botetourt County, 2004 (Box 103, Folder 114)
    - Klockner Pentaplast of America, Inc., Wythe County, 2002-2005 (Box 103, Folder 115)
    - Kollmorgen, City of Radford, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 116)
    - LSK Smoked Turkey, City of Harrisonburg, 2005 (Box 103, Folder 117)
    - Linamar-TransGear Manufacturing, Botetourt County, 2005 (Box 103, Folder 118)
    - Lindstrand Technologies, Halifax County, 2004-2005 (Box 103, Folder 119)
    - Lineal Technologies, Franklin County, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 120)
    - Lockheed Marting, City of Suffolk, 2003 (Box 103, Folder 121)
    - Lohmann Corporation, Orange County, 2002 (Box 103, Folder 122)
    - Luna nanoMaterials, City of Danville, 2003-2004 (Box 103, Folder 123)
    - M and H Plastics, Frederick County, 2003-2004 (Box 103, Folder 124)
    - MLP-VOIP Systems, City of Bedford, 2004 (Box 103, Folder 125)
    - Morgan Stanley, Henrico County, 2002 (Box 103, Folder 126)
    - Project MX (Synthes), 2004 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - MZM, Inc., City of Martinsville, 2003 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Maersk/APM Terminals, Inc., City of Portsmouth, 2004 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - MasterBrand Cabinets, Inc., Henry County, 2003-2004 (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - Meadwestvaco, City of Buena Vista, 2005 (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - Mediatech, Inc., Prince William County, 2004 (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - Merillat Industries, Culpeper County, 2004 (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - MeriStar, Arlington County, 2002 (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - Metal Industries, Inc., Patrick County, 2002 (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - Micron Technology, City of Manassas, 2005 (Box 104, Folder 10)
    - Mid-Mountain Foods, Inc., Washington County, 2004-2005 (Box 104, Folder 11)
    - Midpaco, Scott County, 2004 (Box 104, Folder 12)
    - Project Midwest Big Box (Cabela's), Wythe County, 2003 (Box 104, Folder 13)
    - Project Mist (MedImmune, Inc.), Chesterfield and Prince William Counties, 2005 (Box 104, Folder 14)
    - Mitsubishi Heavy Industries, 2002 (Box 104, Folder 15)
    - Mod-U-Kraf Homes, LLC, Franklin County, 2005 (Box 104, Folder 16)
    - Money Mailer, City of Franklin, 2003 (Box 104, Folder 17)
    - Montreal Compressors, Chesterfield County, 2005 (Box 104, Folder 18)
    - Morgan-McClure Motorsports, Washington County, 2005 (Box 104, Folder 19)
    - Mullican Flooring, Inc., Wise County, 2002 (Box 104, Folder 20)
    - Perryman Company, Montgomery County or Pulaski County, 2005 (Box 104, Folder 21)
    - Narricot Industries, L.P., Southampton County and Mecklenburg County, 2002 and 2005 (Box 104, Folder 22)
    - Narroflex, Inc., Patrick County, 2002 (Box 104, Folder 23)
    - NASA Shared Services Center, City of Newport News, 2004 (Box 104, Folder 24)
    - Noland Distribution Center, Prince George County, 2002 (Box 104, Folder 25)
    - Northeast Cooperative, Inc., 2002 (Box 104, Folder 26)
    - Owens-Illinois, Campbell County, 2003 (Box 104, Folder 27)
    - Peebles, Inc., Mecklenburg County, 2004-2005 (Box 104, Folder 28)
    - Princeton BioMeditech Corporation, Albemarle County, 2005 (Box 104, Folder 29)
    - Nabi Biopharmaceuticals, Prince William County, 2004 (Box 104, Folder 30)
    - Navy Federal Credit Union (NCFU), Frederick County, 2004 (Box 104, Folder 31)
    - Power Systems International, Inc., Rockbridge County, 2002 (Box 104, Folder 32)
    - Princeton BioMeditech, Albemarle County, 2003 (Box 104, Folder 33)
    - Project Printer (RR Donnelley), City of Lynchburg, 2003 (Box 104, Folder 34)
    - Purity Foods, Inc., Wise County and Russell County, 2005 (Box 104, Folder 35)
    - Recreational Equipment, Inc., Shenandoah County, 2005 (Box 104, Folder 36)
    - Reline America, Smyth County, 2005-2006 (Box 104, Folder 37)
    - Renold, plc, City of Hampton, 2004 (Box 104, Folder 38)
    - Reynolds Wheels International Virginia, Inc., Russell County, 2003 (Box 104, Folder 39)
    - RD Group LLC, Mecklenburg County, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - RJJ Tire, Inc., Shenandoah County, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - S and M Brands, Lunenburg County, 2002 (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - Savannah Management Group, Bedford County, 2002 (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - Safire Aircraft Company, City of Newport News, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - Schrader-Bridgeport International, Inc., Campbell County, 2003 (Box 105, Folder 6)
    - Service Center Metals, Prince George Cunty, 2005 (Box 105, Folder 7)
    - Sherwood Brands, LLC, 2002 (Box 105, Folder 8)
    - Siemens VDO Automotive Corporation, City of Newport News, 2002-2003 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Sierra Military Health Services, City of Chesapeake, 2003 (Box 105, Folder 10)
    - Silicon Semiconductor, City of Richmond, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 11)
    - Smithfield Foods, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 12)
    - Smyth Companies, Inc., Bedford and Bedford County, 2005 (Box 105, Folder 13)
    - Snack Alliance, Inc., City of Bristol, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 14)
    - Project Southbound (Longwood Elastomers), Wythe County, 2003 (Box 105, Folder 15)
    - Specialty Blades, City of Staunton, 2005 (Box 105, Folder 16)
    - Spierent Communications, 2002 (Box 105, Folder 17)
    - Project Spyglass, Prince William County, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 18)
    - Star Scientific, Inc., Mecklenburg County, 2002 (Box 105, Folder 19)
    - SYFAN, City of Suffolk, 2002 (Box 105, Folder 20)
    - StarTek, City of Lynchburg, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 21)
    - StarTeck, City of Petersburg, 2005 (Box 105, Folder 22)
    - Steel Fab, Inc., Washington County, 2002 (Box 105, Folder 23)
    - Stihl Incorporated, City of Virginia Beach, 2003-2005 (Box 105, Folder 24)
    - Stihl Incorporated (Stihl 3), City of Virginia Beach, 2005 (Box 105, Folder 25)
    - Project Sugar (Eli Lilly and Company), 2002 (Box 105, Folder 26)
    - Project Sunrise, City of Petersburg, 2002-2003 (Box 105, Folder 27)
    - Sunshine Mills, Halifax County, 2003 (Box 105, Folder 28)
    - Superior Walls, Amelia County, 2003 (Box 105, Folder 29)
    - Sysco Corporation, Front Royal, 2002 (Box 105, Folder 30)
    - SYSCO Corporation, Mecklenburg County, 2002-2004 (Box 105, Folder 31)
    - TMD Friction, Pulaski County, 2002 (Box 105, Folder 32)
    - TMD Fricktion, Roanoke County, 2002 (Box 105, Folder 33)
    - Target Corporation, City of Suffolk, 2002 (Box 105, Folder 34)
    - Target Corporation, Pittsylvania County, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 35)
    - Tecton Products LLC, Roanoke County, 2005 (Box 105, Folder 36)
    - TEDS, Inc., Smyth and Washington Counties, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 37)
    - Telvista, City of Danville, 2003-2004 (Box 105, Folder 38)
    - Ten Oaks, LLC, Patrick County, 2005 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Teves, Culpeper County, 2002 (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - Texturing Services, Inc., Henry County, 2004-2005 (Box 106, Folder 3)
    - Therma-Tru, Spotsylvania County, 2003 (Box 106, Folder 4)
    - ThinOptX, Town of Abingdon, 2002 (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - Tiger Truck, Smyth County, 2002 (Box 106, Folder 6)
    - Timken Corporation, Campbell County, 2005-2006 (Box 106, Folder 7)
    - Project Toano (Dow Corning), James City County, 2003 (Box 106, Folder 8)
    - Project To Do List (American Institute of Certified Public Accountants), City of Newport News or City of Virginia Beach, 2005 (Box 106, Folder 9)
    - Toll Integrated Systems, Greensville County, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 10)
    - Tracker Machine Group, Henry County, 2002 (Box 106, Folder 11)
    - Trader electronic Media, City of Norfolk, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 12)
    - Tredegar Films, Patrick County, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 13)
    - Trinity Packaging Corporation, Franklin County, 2002 (Box 106, Folder 14)
    - Turman Hardwood Flooring, Inc., City of Galax, 2005 (Box 106, Folder 15)
    - USG Corporation, City of Norfolk, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 16)
    - United Health Group, City of Roanoke, 2005 (Box 106, Folder 17)
    - Universal Fiber Systems, Washington County, 2005 (Box 106, Folder 18)
    - Universal Food and Beverage Company, Grayson County, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 19)
    - Project Uplink (Discovery Communications, Ind.), Prince William County, 2002-2003 (Box 106, Folder 20)
    - U.S. Foodservice, Inc., City of Salem, 2002 (Box 106, Folder 21)
    - Utility Trailer Manufacturing Company, Smyth County, 2003-2004 (Box 106, Folder 22)
    - Project Value (Wal-Mart), Rockingham County, 2002 (Box 106, Folder 23)
    - Veggie Patch, Greensville County, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 24)
    - VeriSign, Inc., Tazewell County, 2002 (Box 106, Folder 25)
    - Virgin USA, Inc., Fairfax County, 2003-2004 (Box 106, Folder 26)
    - Project Voyager, City of Petersburg, 2005 (Box 106, Folder 27)
    - Wachovia Securities, City of Richmond and Henrico County, 2003-2004 (Box 106, Folder 28)
    - Wal-Mart Stores East, LP, Rockingham County, 2003 (Box 106, Folder 29)
    - Wal-Mart, James City County, 2003-2004 (Box 106, Folder 30)
    - Weil McLain, Henry County, 2003 (Box 106, Folder 31)
    - Windsor Mill, Surry County, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 32)
    - Wolseley, City of Newport News, 2005 (Box 106, Folder 33)
    - Wytheville Technologies, Wythe County, Bland County and Town of Wytheville, 2003 (Box 106, Folder 34)
    - Yorktown Cabinetry, Inc., City of Danville, 2004-2005 (Box 106, Folder 35)
    - Project Zee Two (T-Mobile), Montgomery County or City of Radford, 2003 (Box 106, Folder 36)
  - Governor's Opportunity Fund/Virginia Investment Partnership
    - Eli Lilly and Company, Prince William County, 2002-2005 (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Framatome ANP, Inc., City of Lynchburg, 2003-2005 (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Frito-Lay, Inc., City of Lynchburg, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - General Dynamics, Prince William County and Warren County, 2002-2003 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Lee Commericial Carpet, Rockbridge County, 2005 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Metalsa, Botetourt County, 2003 (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Parker-Hannifin, City of Lynchburg, 2002-2003 (Box 107, Folder 7)
    - PepsiCo., Inc., Wythe County, 2005 (Box 107, Folder 8)
    - Philip Morris, City of Richmond and Henrico County, 2004 (Box 107, Folder 9)
    - Polymer Group, Inc., City of Waynesboro, 2005 (Box 107, Folder 10)
    - Rolls-Royce North America, City of Danville or James City County, 2003 (Box 107, Folder 11)
    - Wella Corporation, Henrico County, 2004 (Box 107, Folder 12)
  - Virginia Investment Partnership
    - Adolph Coors, Rockingham County, 2004-2005 (Box 107, Folder 13)
    - American Woodmark, Washington County and Smyth County, 2003 (Box 107, Folder 14)
    - Booz Allen Hamilton, Fairfax County, 2004 (Box 107, Folder 15)
    - Coors Brewing Company, Rockingham County, 2004-2005 (Box 107, Folder 16)
    - Covance, Inc., Prince William County, 2005 (Box 107, Folder 17)
    - DeGussa/Goldschmidt Chemical, City of Hopewell, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 18)
    - DuPont, Inc., Chesterfield County, 2003 (Box 107, Folder 19)
    - Honeywell, Chesterfield County, 2004-2005 (Box 107, Folder 20)
    - H.P. Hood, Inc., Frederick County, 2003-2004 (Box 107, Folder 21)
    - Interbake Foods LLC, Warren County, 2005 (Box 107, Folder 22)
    - Merck and Co., Inc., Rockingham County, 2004-2005 (Box 107, Folder 23)
    - Morningstar Foods, Rockingham County, 2004 (Box 107, Folder 24)
    - Printpack, Inc., City of Newport News, 2005 (Box 107, Folder 25)
    - Rowe Furniture, Montgomery County, 2004 (Box 107, Folder 26)
    - United States Gypsum Company, City of Norfolk, 2005 (Box 107, Folder 27)
    - Universal Leaf, Inc., City of Danville, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 28)
    - Wyeth Pharmaceuticals, Henrico County, 2004 (Box 107, Folder 29)
  - Tobacco Regional Opportunity Fund
    - Activewear, Inc., Henry County, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 30)
    - Alpha Omega Publications, Smyth County, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 31)
    - Appomattox River Manufacturing Company, Charlotte County, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 32)
    - AT and T Wireless, Russell County, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 33)
    - Essel Propack, City of Danville, 2002-2005 (Box 107, Folder 34)
    - Greenridge Environmental Corporation, Lunenburg County, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 35)
    - Knauss Foods, Henry County, 2002 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Owens Illinois, Town of Altavista, 2002 (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - Reliable Automatic Sprinkler Co., Inc., Franklin County, 2002-2003 (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - Verizon Communications, Wise County, 2002 (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - Visador, Smyth County, 2002-2003 (Box 108, Folder 5)
    - Project Wake (Active Wear/Major League), Henry County, 2002 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence
    - 2001 (Box 108, Folder 7)
    - 2002 (Box 108, Folder 8)
    - 2003 (Box 108, Folder 9)
    - 2004-2005 (Box 108, Folder 10)
- Series IX. Special Projects-Virginia Economic Development Partnership, 1994-2002,(bulk 2001-2002)., Extent: 1 cu. ft. (Box 109)
  This series contains correspondence with prospective companies and organizations interested in participating in the Virginia Economic Development Partnership program during the Allen, Gilmore and Warner administrations. The records detail plans, concerns and questions regarding the feasibility of government fund investments in special projects/events and companies. The Aviation World's Fair highlights concerns with the success and cost of this project and includes correspondence with Virginia's representatives, mayors, and county supervisors on the success of such an enterprise. There are also travel records that doucment the cost incured by the state to send various state officials to France to study the Paris Air Show.
  This series also documents Virginia's efforts to obtain the 2012 Olympics for Washington D.C. There is correspondence between the Secretary Michael J. Schewel and leaders of the business community and Governor Mark Warner's highlighting efforts to secure the Olympics for the District. There are discussions of costs, bid proposals and the overall impact to the entire community.
  There is a complete record for the memorandum of agreement and understanding between the Commonwealth of Virginia and Volvo-GM Heavy Truck Corporation to create jobs in the state of Virginia. This agreement dates back to Governor George Allen's administration and outlines the various relationship changes based on economic conditions. The agreement stipulated certain conditions must be met in order for the company to receive state funding, subsequent layoff announcements presented a problem for the Commonwealth and Pulaski County, the home of the Volvo-GM factory.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by company or special event.
  - Aviation World's Fair Correspondence, 2001-2002. (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Aviation World's Fair Memorandum of Agreement, 2000-2002. (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - Aviation World's Fair Paris Air Show Financial Information, 2001. (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - Aviation World's Fair Status Report Economic, 2002. (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - Aviation World's Fair Vision, 2002-2003. (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Barboursville Mining Constituent Correspondence, 2002. (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - Barboursville Mining General Shale Products, 2002. (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Barboursville Mining-Newsclippings, 2002. (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - Barboursville Mining-Newsclippings, 2002. (Box 109, Folder 8A (Legal Folder))
  - Barboursville Mining- Friends of Barboursville, 2002. (Box 109, Folder 9)
  - Microelectronics Consortium, 1999-2000. (Box 109, Folder 10)
  - Olympic 2012, 2002. (Box 109, Folder 11)
  - Olympic 2012, 2001-2002. (Box 109, Folder 12)
  - Olympic 2012, 2002. (Box 109, Folder 13)
  - Olympic 2012 Games Bid-Process, 2001-2002. (Box 109, Folder 14)
  - Olympic 2012 Games Candidate City Agreement, 1998-2000. (Box 109, Folder 15)
  - Olympic 2012 Games Connecting Communities Hosting History-Executive Summary, 2000. (Box 109, Folder 16)
  - Olympic 2012 Games Greater Washington Exploratory Committee, 1998. (Box 109, Folder 17)
  - Olympic 2012 Games Hosting 2004 U.S. Olympic Team Trials, 2001. (Box 109, Folder 18)
  - Olympic 2012 Games Information Packet, 2001-2002. (Box 109, Folder 19)
  - Olympic 2012 Games Media, 2000-2002. (Box 109, Folder 20)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Coalition-Board of Directors, 1999-2000 (Box 109, Folder 21)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Coalition-Board of Directors, 1999 (Box 109, Folder 22)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Coalition-Court Case, 1999-2000 (Box 109, Folder 23)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Coalition-Economic Impact of Hosting 2012 Olympic Games, 2000 (Box 109, Folder 24)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Fund Raising Booklet, 1999 (Box 109, Folder 25)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 General Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 109, Folder 26)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Government Affairs Committee, 2000 (Box 109, Folder 27)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Coalition Information Booklet, 2001 (Box 109, Folder 28)
  - Olympic 2012 Washington Baltimore Regional 2012 Coalition Strategic Plan, 1999 (Box 109, Folder 29)
  - Short Pump Town Center Community Development Authority, 2001 (Box 109, Folder 30)
  - Software Factory, 1998-1999 (Box 109, Folder 31)
  - Virginia Advanced Shipbuilding and Carrier Integration Center, 2000-2001 (Box 109, Folder 32)
  - Virginia Conference on World Trade (46th), 1994 (Box 109, Folder 33)
  - Virginia River Country, 1998 (Box 109, Folder 34)
  - Volvo-GM, 1995-2000 (Box 109, Folder 35)
  - Volvo-GM, 1994 (Box 109, Folder 36)
  - Volvo-GM, 1994 (Box 109, Folder 37)
  - Volvo-GM, Part II., 1994 (Box 109, Folder 38)
  - World Congress on Information Technology, 1998 (Box 109, Folder 39)
  - World Congress on Information Technology, 1999-2000 (Box 109, Folder 40)